RISHABH MODI

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING STUDENT

OBJECTIVE

Software Engineering student with a year of professional experience and a strong background in web application development actively seeking an internship for Summer 2018.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

Experience working on team projects both in course and at work with internal and external users.

Strong communication skills to discuss and understand over phone and in person.

Well versed with Software development practices through work experience and course work.

Adept with Java, Python, C, C++, HTML, AJAX, JavaScript, Node-JS, Express-JS, Open Modelica and Microsoft Office.

Adept with photo/video editing using tools as Photoshop, Lightroom, PremierePro, and AfterEffects.

VITALS

1255 East University Drive Tempe, AZ 85281

+1(510)-309-2955

rishabh277@yahoo.com

EXPERIENCE

WIZZ O TECH, INDIA

FEBRUARY 2017 – JUNE 2017

- Developed a service which connected local service providers and users based on location data.
- Implemented Google maps API to provide real-time navigation facility.
- Led the project management and coordinated with the product owner to flesh out the application requirements.

SOFTVAN, INDIA

JULY 2015 - JANUARY 2016

- Developed a Library management application using the Express-js framework.
- Designed an interactive and user-friendly interface using Pug-js UI templates.
- Improved the application scalability by implementing asynchronous request handlers which helped to serve twice the number of server requests.
- Collaborated with the team members to verify the usability of the application with respect to the user requirements.

EDUCATION

ARIZONA STATE UNIVERSITY, TEMPE, AZ

AUGUST 2017 - MAY 2019

Master of Science: Software Engineering

GUJARAT TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY, AHMEDABAD, INDIA

JUNE 2013 - APRIL 2017

Bachelor of Engineering: Computer Science (GPA: 3.46)

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

WEATHER APP

NOVEMBER 2017

- Constructed HTML5/JavaScript application using client-side MVC model.
- The app displayed list of cities and their associated weather data gathered from OpenWeatherMap API.
- The data was retrieved and parsed out of the JSON via an AJAX call to implement a Restful behavior.

CLUEDO GAME

OCTOBER 2017

- Developed a single page web app using browser centric MVC pattern.
- The game handled user interaction and browser events through DOM manipulation.
- Implemented browser storage to maintain game session state for respective users.